It's a point that can feel at once
entirely benile and wholly offensive. We
either know it already or may wse at
such an overly direct mention.
High-minded people can be especially
perturbed and have been since the
dialogues of Plato in the sermons of St.
Paul. True love is about connection at
the highest levels. It's about shared
interests, compatible world views, and
alignment on politics and the ends of
life. We do have bodies naturally and
certain urges along with them, but they
do not and must not dominate the choices
of the wise, except of course that in
the clearest terms they should, for we
are never more benile and obtuse than
when we refuse to give low priorities
their due. We eat, we fart, we burp, and
to put it very gently, we need to make
love. And we need to succeed at
relationships to do it very winningly at
the level of ideas rather than
performance and rather often in order to
feel close, in order to feel acceptable
to ourselves, in order to reconnect with
our bodies, in order to feel welcomed by
our partner, in order to ease the
tensions of having large complex minds
that believe they know more than they
do. For all of these reasons, we need to
make love. Yet, how often, and
especially in the priorities of the
so-called intelligent, is this need
either relegated or ignored? There are
so many other considerations when we
meet someone new. Have they read Toltoy
or Kavafi? Would they get on with our
sister? Do they like Bob Dylan? Would
our friends like them? Are they as tidy
or as messy as we are? What do they
earn? How tall are they? What can easily
get lost is a much more fundamental
question. How good is the sex? And here
we need to admit there are vast
variations. Sex is not one thing, though
it takes a lot of luck or experience to
realize this may be the case. We need
once in our lives to have really enjoyed
superlative sex in order to have a
benchmark by which to measure its varied
instances. There are ecstatic, passable,
and very forgettable sorts. There's the
kind of sex that unfolds when the same
fantasies excite us. When the same
traumas were sublimated into kinks, when
compatible childhood wounds generate
erotic currents, when we too want very
much to do that thing with the
blindfold, the Kashmir jumper, or the
stripey socks. We too want to think
about the glances in the restaurant, the
caresses underwater, or the quiet
tension in the library stacks. There is
either alignment or there isn't. far
more than we can admit. When a couple
break up, when expensive lawyers are
called, we don't need to search for
explanations in the realm of values and
ends. We need to look squarely at the
love making. Did it happen often enough?
Did two people want it equally? Were
they each other's types? What were the
two kinks? And the tragedy is that so
often the problem lay in the very place
the couple could not bear to explore out
of a misplaced sense of what could
matter. They didn't want to think about
their so-called perverted sides. Neither
side wanted to own up to what turned
them on in private. They thought they
could overcome the shame of their
stranger visions by simply being very
nice. They believed sex wasn't in the
end as important as finding someone who
also loved modern art or canoeing. And
thereby they destroyed a substantial
portion of their lives. The more
experience we have, the more we're
likely to take seriously what every
adolescent knows. Sex is very
interesting, very strange, and very key.
We may be clever enough, but true
intelligence means properly letting our
baser, blunter, and more compelling
urges have their way.