You got to go.
>> Okay. I'm just asking. You can't push.
Okay.
They just literally pushed me out. Nick
Shirley, I hope you see this video.
Please come to Columbus, Ohio. And if
you come to Columbus, Ohio, you will
find the exact same fraud. More Somali
fraud has been exposed out of Ohio. This
is getting out of hand and they're all
being exposed.
>> You get money through the state of Ohio.
doesn't matter.
>> This is a this is a money that gets
matter.
>> According to one Midwestern Rhino
Republican governor, apparently fraud is
just part of doing business. Now,
>> it's a daycare center owned by uh
Somalians and stuff like that.
>> Have you ever seen any kids in this
place here?
>> No, not that I know of. I just seen it
the building itself. I've never seen
nobody come out the building or go in
the building.
>> You've never seen anybody over there?
>> No, not at all. Everyone has been
talking about Minnesota next. Surely the
empty dayc care is in millions or
potentially billions of dollars gone.
But we're going to be talking about Ohio
cuz that might be next. That might be
Minnesota 2.0 because right now people
are walking into daycare centers in
Columbus, Ohio and they're seeing the
same exact things. No kids, locked
doors, people getting aggressive when
asked basic questions. So right now we
are in front of the Great Minds Learning
Academy. This is one of the many daycare
centers, learning centers here in
Columbus, Ohio that are associated with
the Somali community. So, this place
here is the first place we're going to
knock and we're going to see if anybody
picks up or answers the door. Let's see.
So, it's locked. We're ringing the
doorbell here. Knocking on the door.
Nobody's picking up. So, we're not sure
what the hell is going on here, but
we're going to we're going to get out of
here now. There's somebody over there.
How you doing, sir? Did you you know
anything about this place here?
>> It's a daycare center owned by uh
Somalians and stuff like that.
>> Do you ever see any kids there?
>> Not cuz they use the back door. So I
want to know if they
>> they use the back door.
>> Yeah. I never seen nobody come in. But
they use the back door.
>> But But have you ever seen any kids? You
live around here?
>> Yeah. Yeah. On this building right here.
>> Oh, you're in this building?
>> Yeah.
>> You're in this building, too?
>> Let me ask you, have have you ever seen
any kids in this place here?
>> No, not that I know of. They use the
back. So, I've never seen nobody come
out the front.
>> You also see some potential SNAP
benefits that's being taken away, too.
So,
>> more Somali fraud has been exposed out
of Ohio. This is getting out of hand,
and they're all being exposed. Listen to
this. Somali in Ohio are allegedly
running EBT fraud rings using SNAP
benefits to stalk their restaurants,
skimming cards to make millions. More
than 34,000 Ohio households have been
duped out of nearly 17 million in SNAP
benefits from June 2023 to December 2024
with Somali migrant criminals using
scheming devices at grocery devices at
grocery stores to clone magnetic strip
cards and steal the money according to
the Ohio Department of Job and Family
Services. In addition, a recent report
details how Somali owned restaurants and
grocery stores in Columbus are
exploiting benefits. According to the
report, migrants own restaurants with
attached grocery stores that they own.
They buy their ingredients in bulk with
SNAP from their grocery stores, then
funnel the food to the restaurants where
they sell it for cash. One report claims
that the Somali migrant men who own the
restaurants typically have numerous
wives. That's crazy. They only have to
claim their first wife so that
subsequent wives are able to collect
welfare benefits that are then used to
prop up the stores. And
>> yeah, they're Muslims and usually
Muslims are able to have more than one
wife. But you can see that they're just
they just know how to finesse the
system. They they're looking they're
going through loopholes. They know
exactly where to to go and find exactly
how to exploit and and really run away
with it by just connecting everything
their families to the business using all
these resources to extract more
resources out of the taxpayer. It it's
crazy.
>> This comes as as of a 2022 audit of
Somali Community Link. A Columbus
nonprofit funded in 2020 by Somali
migrants exposed a reported $2.3 million
in fraud from federal emergency rental
assistance program funds. The
investigation flagged missing rental
aid, violations of cash management
protocols, and in inadequate fraud
safeguards. Despite these failures, the
group tied to local politician via
campaign donations secured $350,000 in
state funding last summer for a
community center plus $100,000 from
Columbus for housing and youth programs.
Back in 2020, Somali brothers Hassan and
Abdurahim Norizo, former owners of Tofi
Market Market in Columbus, were indicted
for a 9-year snap in wick fraud
conspiracy totaling over $10 million.
The duo allegedly swapped benefits for
cash at half the value. Abdurahim, who
oversaw operations, was sentenced to two
years behind bars. Hassan got house
arrest and probation after a guilty
plea. So, you can defraud SNAP benefits
for $10 million and you get house arrest
and probation. Only if you're Somalian,
I guess, because if I do that and you
and I do that, we're going to go to jail
for a long, long time.
>> This is why it matters. Columbus has the
second largest Somalia population in the
country right behind Minnesota. So, in
this video, we're going to talk about
Ohio and people are asking the same
question. Is the same scam happening
again or is it possible it's even worse?
Let's get into it.
>> Is this an attack on immigrants?
>> This is an attack on fraud here in the
state of Ohio.
>> This Ohio lawmaker making some serious
demands on what he calls reports of
fraud within publicly funded daycarees
in Columbus. You can see that this place
is just a total dump.
>> More people are targeting Somali owned
daycarees looking for kids and
suggesting fraud. Would you call these
video clips allegations or would you
call them proof of fraud?
>> That's just an allegation of fraud.
>> Now, state rep. Josh Williams, who is
running for US Congress, sent this
letter to the Ohio Department of
Children and Youth, calling for more
unannounced inspections and attendance
audits of all publicly funded daycarees
in Ohio. He also wants to pull state and
federal funds on the suspicion of fraud
opposed to a charge or conviction.
>> We're saying the funds have to stop
until you prove that it is not fraud
moving forward. I mean, you go through
some of these inspection reports and you
do see non-compliance
when it comes to attendance. Are you
suggesting there is widespread fraud
within publicly funded daycare centers
in Columbus, especially those Somali
owned?
>> What we're alleging is that there is
widespread reporting of potential fraud
uh from individuals on the ground.
>> Columbus isn't random. It has thousands
of daycare centers, home health care
agencies, grocery stores, and nonprofits
tied to government funding. Most people
are just trying to survive. Most are not
doing anything wrong. But history shows
that a small group exploiting weak
oversight to steal millions and millions
of dollars. That is why people inside
Ohio are starting to speak up. They're
saying that this looks exactly like
Minnesota. Same behavior, same
resistance to questions, same money
streams. So these individuals tried to
report the fraud that was happening in
Ohio and then eventually came to me to
say that we're watching providers rubber
stamp paperwork for home health. So in
Ohio and there's many states like this
uh Pennsylvania and other states too
where you can go in and you can say my
aging parent needs a home health care
and I want to provide it. So the state
will as long as a doctor has approved it
continue to pay you. It could be for 10
hours, 12 hours, up to 24 when it's
critical care. So you could sit at home
without caring for an elderly parent who
really doesn't need it, make about $75
to $90,000 a year. Now you add two
parents, that's 180. Now you add your
in-laws, $ 250. You continue to add this
and you wonder what are the services
being provided. So a lot of providers
came and said fraud is occurring because
we said we weren't going to rubber stamp
this paperwork. So they went to other
providers, their home healthcare network
saying, "We'll make it worth your
while." Well, sounds like a kickback to
me. So, we really need to investigate
the Medicaid system and how much it's
increased since the Somalian population
came and who really needs critical care
cuz that's meant for our disabled, our
elderly, and people who really need it,
not to just live up our system. And
that's what's happening in Ohio. I think
it's ridiculous. I think it's
despicable. But authorities are now
looking at it from the attorney
general's office to the US attorney's
office. I flagged them all because this
is Ohio tax dollars and we have to take
it seriously. I'm tired of people
telling me, "Well, this is the way it's
always been. It's subjective and we
can't really check." No, you can't.
Audit America, audit Ohio now. And I'm
pushing for that in every single state.
>> Yeah, definitely. I think that there's
going to be or there needs to be more
invested in checking to see if everyone
is doing it right. Regardless of if
you're a Somalian or whatever, there's
tons of fraud happening across the
country. At least some of the Somalian
fraud that we've seen, it's so blatantly
obvious that they're it's fraud that
they're they're not even clever about
it. But at least the first selection of
fraud that you going to you can quickly
eliminate because they're just they're
doing it right in front of everyone's
face. They don't really care how it
looks. So, similar to Nick Shirley,
people are walking up to daycare during
business hours and they're asking a very
simple question. How do I enroll my
child? That said, no accusations, no
confrontation, but you can look at the
reaction.
>> Um, you know, how much does it cost?
>> Whoa.
>> You can't just grab myself.
>> The First Choice Childc Care LLC.
>> Look at this. Why is there
>> with a uh
Casim Brothers
semitr in the parking lot.
That's what you want to see uh when
you're dropping your kid off for child
care is a semitr.
See if we can. It's locked.
>> Yeah, which makes sense. I mean,
>> yeah, it should be locked. Yeah,
>> most daycarees I've been to, they are
locked.
>> Legally, they should be protect the
kids.
>> Yeah.
Lots of
security cameras. Notice the trend at
all these locations.
>> Camera up there. Camera over there.
>> There's no cars in the parking lot. So,
>> they're open 7 days a week though and
there's no signage to say
>> say it's closed. So there's
and then this is kind of the
neighborhood you're looking at
next door.
Oh, we have another daycare center right
>> Bright Futures.
So I guess we can just Oops.
They must have started putting these
cards in
>> fire property. No trespassing.
This one also has camera thing.
>> It's interesting that they boarded all
of this up too. So you can't
>> you can't see inside at all in any of
these
>> tons of daycarees um where at least this
is open so you can see
>> they have a nice lobby entry. Yeah.
>> Hi. Um I was wondering are you open
today?
Do you have any paperwork? I just wanted
to look up your enrollment for a
three-year-old.
My name is Nah.
Heat. Heat.
I'm sorry.
>> Am I what?
>> You're going to send somebody?
>> No.
>> Okay.
Okay. They want us to stop recording for
um for
>> Okay, that's fine.
>> Price after we fill the application.
>> So, how much does it cost?
>> I don't understand.
>> Just asking how how much it cost to go
to daycare here.
>> Thank you.
Is it?
>> Um, you know how much does it cost?
>> Whoa.
>> You can't just grab myself.
>> Like that's insane. Their hours are
Monday through Friday.
>> Say they should be open. And they
literally asked if I'm recording and
then pushed me. That's insane.
There's clearly children in there.
I just don't think you should put your
hands on somebody and push them out.
>> No.
>> Safe.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm just wondering why you're pushing
me.
No, the lady literally put her hands on
me and pushed me. I just had a couple
questions.
>> Well, if they did that, why did you call
the police?
>> I mean, I'm not going to call the
police. I'm just trying to ask a few
questions.
>> If they push you, you should have called
the police.
>> Okay, that's a good idea. I should call
the police. Okay, thank you so much.
Happy New Year.
>> This is a question. How do you enroll
How do you enroll your children here?
You can't do that.
No kids.
So, how how the how can I enroll my
children? It says you get you get public
money through
>> you get public money through Ohio. You
get money through the state of Ohio.
>> This is a this is a money that gets
matter.
>> They won't explain enrollment. They get
defensive. They get angry. They
physically push people out of the
building and that's not normal. Anyone
who has children, you call a daycare,
you call a school, they can't wait to
tell you all the information. They'll
schedule a tour. You come by, check the
place out. Most legit daycarees want
kids. They advertise. They explain the
pricing. They hand you the paperwork.
But here we see is locked doors, no
visible children, no clear enrollment
process, and a lot of aggressive
behavior. These are the same red flags
that we saw in Minnesota. Different
state, but the same playbook. Because
right now we see a pattern, and patterns
do matter. In Minnesota, investigators
found daycare billing for kids that
weren't there, payments tied to weak
verification systems, little real-time
oversight. Ohio seems like they're using
the same funding structures, and the
locals are saying you can't enroll your
kids, no one's going to answer your
door, auditors are going to get pushed
out, and the money just keeps flowing.
That's why people are asking questions,
not because of race, not because of
politics, because this is taxpayer
money. This concern didn't come out of
nowhere. Ohio already has major SNAP and
food snap. Fraud cases, documented
cases, court records, millions of
dollars, grocery stores swapping
benefits for cash, inflated
transactions, fraud lasting years before
anyone steps in. Now, the governor is
not really taking this very seriously.
He says investigations are happening. He
says that people shouldn't jump to
conclusions based on viral videos. But
the critics are saying Minnesota said
the same thing. Oversight usually comes
in way too late. According to one
Midwestern Rhino Republican governor,
apparently fraud is just part of doing
business now. And that's the message
coming out of the Ohio governor's office
after questions about potential massive
fraud in his state. When asked about the
taxpayer funded daycare centers and the
fraud, the response, well, it wasn't
shock and it wasn't urgency. It was,
"This has been known for decades and
therefore it's just a cost of doing
business." That line alone right there
deserves a slap across the face from the
taxpayer. According to the governor
spokesperson, if you're surprised people
might defraud public daycare programs,
well, that's on you for being naive
because everyone knows that just happens
and everyone just has to live with it.
And meanwhile, Ohio spends over $800
million a year on childare assistance.
$800 million. That's almost $1 billion.
That's not monopoly money. That's your
paycheck. That's the taxes they take
from you every pay period. And here's
where this starts to get a little
uncomfortable. If fraud has been known
for decades, that means two things can't
be both true. Either the oversight is
failing or the fraud it's being
tolerated. Because calling something the
cost of doing business, that's not
accountability. It's turning a blind eye
to the fraud. And why would you do such
a thing? Maybe you're in on it. Now,
we're expected to budget and we're
expected to document every dollar and
you're expected to follow the rules. But
when millions, potentially billions,
disappear in public programs, we're told
that's just how it work. We've seen this
with the other governor, even the
Democratic governor, where they want to
always show that they have complete
control of what's going on. We got it.
We know there's fraud, but we're we're
on it. And that's not working for Tim
Walsh, obviously. And I guess with this
governor here, he's trying to do the
same thing. And that is terribly worded.
We shouldn't tolerate fraud. Yes, it
happens, but doesn't mean it needs to be
done to a point where potentially
hundreds of millions of dollars are
being missing. I don't think that's
something that we should tolerate. I
think that's something we should take
very seriously. We should be very angry
about it because a lot of people pay
into a system that's being, you know,
robbed. So that's the So I would say
that for that governor, his tone, for
that governor, that statement just seems
to be very out of touch. And now
lawmakers are calling for investigations
because similar ghost daycare schemes
have already blown up in other states,
which raises a very simple question if
this really is the cost of doing
business. Who exactly decided taxpayers
should be the ones paying it? Aggressive
behavior should trigger immediate
results because people are arguing that
leadership is more focused on keeping
Ohio's image clean than aggressively
exposing problems early. Now, this
governor is Republican governor. So we
see from Democrat governor in Minnesota
to the Republican governor in Ohio,
we're seeing the same issues. They're
not taking it seriously and they're
allowing people to commit fraud. We need
to continue to repeat this that every
dollar stolen is a child that doesn't
get real care, a family that loses
support, and a taxpayer getting robbed.
Minnesota obviously is not a one-off.
This might be just a warning. If Ohio
ignores the signs, this will just get
worse. And we must really take a look in
the entire country to see how far this
extent goes in terms of Medicaid fraud
and the daycare fraud and all this type
of fraud regardless of who is doing it
because the solution isn't hate, it's
audits, transparency, oversight.
Sunlight kills these scams and that's
why so many people are going after
they're going across the country. I've
heard that it's happening in
Massachusetts. We have to talk about
that as well. Let me know if you're in
Ohio. Have you seen this type of thing
happening? Let me know all your thoughts
in the comments below.